# Jaison Binns

Phone: 610.348.4284 | Email: <a href="mailto:binns.jaison@gmail.com">binns.jaison@gmail.com</a> | Linkedin: <a href="mailto:binns.jaison@gmail.com">linkedin.com/in/jaison-binns/</a> |

Portfolio: jaisonbinns.github.io/

# **Summary**

Experienced and versatile Operation Specialist, who focuses on working with C-level decision makers to develop and implement software products with an effective business plan, exceeding revenue goals for over 75% of his clients. Technical communicator, who works cross-functionally with multiple teams to overcome challenges. Passionate and driven entrepreneur, who has launched a freelance software development business.

# Skills

#### **Operations**

- Relationship building and management
- Business analysis & planning
- Technical writer
- Process automation

## Support

- IT Networking
- Hardware Repair
- QA Testing
- Content Management System (CMS)
- Remote File Transfer

#### Other

- C#, Python
- Linux OS
- SQL, MongoDB
- Version control (Git)
- Agile, Scrum
- CLI tooling

# Experience

# GoMoto, Inc. (dba Reynolds & Reynolds) / Operations Engineer

April 2019 - PRESENT, PHILADELPHIA, PA

- Building relationships with key stakeholders and successfully launch the product across their stores.
- Lead the operations teams in resolving hardware and software issues for all clients.
- Created and wrote documentation for multiple knowledge bases (Operations, Support, and Development)
- Compile, analyze and monitor product performance and data for clients exceeding revenue goals for over 75% of clients.
- Automated operational data entry tasks using Python, BeautifulSoup, Selenium, and Excel.

## Self-Employed / Software Design & Development

June 2020 - PRESENT, PHILADELPHIA, PA

- Created websites for a couple local restaurants, which increased pickup orders by 10% in June.
- Designed wireframe, UX/UI mockup, and application prototype using FIGMA for a client resulting in private seed funding.

## Vibespot App, LLC / Founding Member / Business Development

OCTOBER 2018 - APRIL 2019, PHILADELPHIA, PA

- Redesigned the 2.0 UX/UI experience using MS Paint and InVision resulting in 3,000+ app downloads and 10+ venue and collegiate partnerships over 5 months.
- Analyzed user data to develop a new strategic business plan resulting in decreased new user acquisition cost from \$5/user to \$2/user.

## **Education**

**Villanova University / Political Science, Classical Studies, Computer Science (Minor)**May 2018, VILLANOVA, PA

Dean's List, St. Thomas of Villanova Scholar and Comcast Leaders/Achievers Scholarship